sure if you guys aren't tired of hearing
about them let's talk about the brain
organoids what they are and how they can
be used in the simplest terms you might
be familiar with the term stem cell that
essentially means a cell which can be
turned into other types of cells so when
it comes to the human brain organoids we
take skin cells which are more similar
to Flur potent stem cells they can't
become anything but they can become a
lot of things and one of those is
neurons this process is essentially the
same process of a human being being
produced in a womb except we are only
growing the brain as you can see
sometimes they have little eyes that's
the same process that we have when we're
being formed some of the first
researchers who actually made the human
brain organoids found that the longer
that they grew the more complex the
brain waves became and it they found it
very disturbing but after about 60 days
the brain organoids seem to have very
similar brain wave to a pre-term baby
now they did state that we don't really
have brain wave patterns established for
fetuses you know for obvious reasons but
we do have them for pre-term babies this
has led to a lot of ethical concerns
some however are still pushing ahead to
put these little guys on computer chips
and essentially immersing them in an
artificial world so all of the
information that they get is going to be
what we give them that's why when we
made them play Pong we essentially
immersed these little brains into the
Matrix that's all they know and they are
more efficient at learning than AI
models because they are actual neural
activity not the versions of neural
activity that we make in a computer
these little guys also have great
applications for medicine we can
actually look at how medications affect
the brain directly and and in terms of
personalized medicine we could make a
little brain organoid from you and see
how the neurons interact with
medications before we give them to you
they also make great models for disease
we could for example take the preon
diseases which form plaques in the brain
and give them directly to the brain
organoids and see what's actually
happening it's a great way to see what
medications might help it too on a small
scale rather than going through the
entire process of working through mice
and then humans we could just go
directly to the brain organoids assuming
that it's ethical and the ethics is a
big concern we don't know what it's like
in the little brain organoids heads some
say that it's perfectly fine because I
mean they're they're teeny tiny how much
information could possibly be processed
in those little brains others say that
it's a little bit too close to home
however we can still use brain organoids
from other animals M brain organoids are
being used in the US I hope that helps